bloomberg.net 2019-06-30

# Privacy

Bloomberg L.P. and its affiliates (together, “Bloomberg”) respects the privacy rights of our users and is strongly committed to protecting your privacy. This Privacy Policy applies to this Web site, any newsletters subscribed to via this Web site, information collected and provided to Bloomberg when you subscribe digitally to Bloomberg.com or Bloomberg Businessweek at third-party websites and applications, and information collected offline when you subscribe to the print edition of Bloomberg Businessweek, but does not apply to any other product or service of Bloomberg, unless otherwise expressly indicated by Bloomberg (such as by including a link to this Privacy Policy on other Bloomberg websites or on Bloomberg mobile applications).

## Collection and Use of Your Personal Information

Bloomberg, or where relevant a designated service provider, collects personal information that you voluntarily provide on this Web site, on third-party websites and applications when subscribing digitally to Bloomberg.com or Bloomberg Businessweek, or offline in connection with your Bloomberg Businessweek print edition subscription, which may include your name, address, email address, contact information, credit card number, billing information, password etc. For example, Bloomberg or a designated service provider collects personal information when you register on this Web site, request certain Bloomberg services or products, or submit the information to enter a sweepstakes, contest, or other promotion. If you do not provide certain personal information, not all functionality on the site will be available. 

Do not provide information about others unless you are authorized to do so and consent to have all information used, disclosed, and transferred in accordance with this Privacy Policy. By submitting the information about others, you represent and warrant that you are authorized to do so and that you have received authorization from the person about whom you are providing the information and that person has consented to have all information used, disclosed, and transferred in accordance with this Privacy Policy.

We use this information for carefully considered business purposes which also benefit our customers and which include some or all of the following:

  * • to provide our services and products
  * • to communicate with you
  * • to help Bloomberg improve our services and products and develop new services and products
  * • to provide support for our services and products, and for Bloomberg internal quality control purposes
  * • to provide you with offers and promotions about services and products of Bloomberg or of other parties that may be of interest to you
  * • to enhance your experience with this Web site, including to save your preference and login information
  * • to analyze web site usage and analyze use of the Web site
  * • to protect the interests, rights, safety, or property of Bloomberg or others and to monitor compliance with and enforce the terms of any agreement with Bloomberg
  * • to operate our services, products, and systems properly.

We use any credit card or payment information we acquire from you to fulfill your order. You may instruct Bloomberg at any time not to use your personal information covered by this Privacy Policy to provide you with offers and promotions by clicking [here](https://login.bloomberg.com/signup) or, if you are Bloomberg Businessweek subscriber, by clicking on the Bloomberg Businessweek Opt-out [form](https://www.bloomberg.com/email-settings/manage/). You can also update your settings for receiving offers and promotions by clicking [here](https://www.bloomberg.com/email-settings/manage/). Please note that if you exercise choice in this manner, you will continue to receive communications concerning your account and products and services you requested, and in response to any requests for information by you. Please also note that this opt-out process may take some time to complete, consistent with applicable law.

Bloomberg or a designated service provider takes photographs for security purposes and for inclusion the People directory on the BLOOMBERG TERMINAL, which is available to Bloomberg users worldwide.

## Use of Cookies And Other Electronic Tools

Bloomberg and the parties with whom we work (e.g., service providers, business partners, advertisers and advertising servers) may place, view, and/or use “cookies”, Web server logs, Web beacons, or other electronic tools to collect statistical and other information about your use of this Web site and other websites. This information may include information about the IP address of your computer, browser type, language, operating system, your mobile device, device ID, geo-location data, the state or country from which you accessed this Web site, the Web pages visited, the date and the time of a visit, the websites you visited immediately before and after visiting this Web site, the number of links you click within this Web site, the functions you use on this Web site, the databases you view and the searches you request on this Web site, the data you save on or download from this Website and the number of times you view an advertisement.

Bloomberg and the parties with whom we work may use the information collected for various reasons, either on behalf of Bloomberg or for the other parties’ own purposes, including research, analysis, to better serve visitors to this Web site (such as by enabling log-in, providing access to certain sections of this Web site, providing customized content, or presenting online advertising on this Web site or other websites tailored to your interests as described further below), to compile aggregate and anonymous information about usage of this Web site and other websites, other statistics, etc. However, if you have deleted and disabled cookies, these uses will not be possible to the extent they are based on cookie information. To opt out of Google Analytics, including Demographics and Interest Reporting, please click [here](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout). To opt out of Parse.ly analytics, please click [here](http://srv.config.parsely.com/optout).

To assist us with the uses described in this Privacy Policy, information collected about your use of this Web site or other websites may be aggregated, analyzed or combined with personal or other information about you from other online or offline sources. If you prefer that we not combine non-personal information that has been collected, through cookies, about your use of this Web site or other websites with personal or other information about you, then please delete and disable cookies for each browser, on each computer you use to surf the Web.

Most browsers are set to accept cookies by default. If you prefer, you can usually set your browser to disable cookies, or to alert you when cookies are being sent. Likewise, most mobile devices allow you to disable the ability for geo-location information to be collected from your mobile device. The help function on most browsers and mobile devices contains instructions on how to set your browser to notify you before accepting cookies, disable cookies entirely, or disable the collection of geo-location data. You need to set each browser, on each device you use to surf the Web. Thus, if you use multiple browsers (e.g., Chrome, Safari, Internet Explorer, Firefox, etc.), you should repeat this procedure with each one. Similarly, if you connect to the Web from multiple devices (e.g., work and home), you need to set each browser on each device. Depending on your jurisdiction, you may be able to utilize additional cookie management tools. However, if you disable cookies or refuse to accept a request to place a cookie, it is possible that some parts of this Web site, such as the polls, surveys, contests, and product sales, and certain areas of the Web site for which you need to log in, will not function properly, and the advertising you receive when you visit this Web site may not be advertisements tailored to your interests.

## Advertisements

Bloomberg, its designated service providers, or third-party advertisers or their advertising servers may also place or recognize unique cookies on your computer or use other electronic tools in order to help display advertisements that you see on this Web site or on other websites. Information about your visits to, and activity on, this Web site and other websites, an IP address, the number of times you have viewed an advertisement, and other such usage information is used, alone or in combination with other information, to display on your device screen advertisements that may be of particular interest to you. We may use Web beacons, provided by third-party advertising companies, to help manage and optimize our online advertising and product performance. Web beacons enable us to recognize a browser’s cookie when a browser visits this Web site, and to learn which banner ads bring users to this Web site. The use and collection of your information by these third-party service providers, and third-party advertisers and their advertising servers is not covered by this Privacy Policy. BLP adheres to the industry’s Self-Regulatory Principles for Online Behavioral Advertising located [here](http://www.aboutads.info/principles). To “opt out” of advertising cookies placed by participating companies in the Self-Regulatory Program for Online Behavioral Advertising, and thereby limit the tracking of your online activity and the targeted advertising you receive, please click [here](http://www.aboutads.info/). To “opt out” of advertising cookies placed by the Network Advertising Initiative’s (“NAI”) online behavioral advertising member networks, and thereby limit the tracking of your online activity and the targeted advertising you receive, please click [here](http://optout.networkadvertising.org/?c=1#!/). To opt out of advertising cookies for Your Online Choices if you are based in the EU, please click [here](http://youronlinechoices.eu/).

DoubleClick for Publishers and other designated service providers assist Bloomberg with advertisement display functions and related analytics for this Web site. To opt out of Google Analytics for Display Advertising, please click [here](https://adssettings.google.com/authenticated). To opt out of Facebook advertising on OTT devices, please click [here](https://m.facebook.com/ads/preferences/settings).

Note that even if you exercise choice for targeted advertising, you will still receive online advertising.

## Disclosure of Your Personal Information

Bloomberg may share your personal information with our affiliates (including affiliated websites under common ownership or control) and designated service providers, including for the purposes set out in this Privacy Policy. Bloomberg may share with other third parties information about our Web site users, such as your use of this Web site or other websites, and the services provided on this Web site or other websites, but only on an unattributed and aggregate basis. Bloomberg may also share your personal information (excluding security photographs) with a sponsor or other third party (“Third-Party Provider”) that provides you with offers or promotions that may be of interest to you. You may instruct Bloomberg at any time not to share your personal information covered by this Privacy Policy with such Third-Party Providers by clicking [here](https://login.bloomberg.com/third-party-opt-out) or, if you are Bloomberg Businessweek subscriber, by clicking on the Bloomberg Businessweek Opt-out [form](https://www.bloomberg.com/email-settings/manage/). Please note that (i) this opt-out process may take some time to complete, consistent with applicable law; and (ii) even after such opt-out process is completed, your personal information may continue to be shared with our affiliates (including affiliated websites under common ownership or control) and designated service providers.

If you participate in certain features of this Web site (e.g., sharing news stories of interest), please note that any information you or others voluntarily disclose through use of these features, becomes available to the public and/or other users whom you have designated. If you choose to provide access to designated individuals, please be aware that any information you post will be visible to such individuals for their use. Bloomberg is not responsible for the information that you or others choose to disclose publicly on this Web site, and neither Bloomberg’s nor others’ use of such information is subject to this Privacy Policy.

Bloomberg may also disclose your personal information to unaffiliated third parties if we believe in good faith that such disclosure is necessary to: (a) comply with any applicable law, rule, or regulation, or in response to a subpoena, court order, or other legal process, subject to [Bloomberg’s Law Enforcement Data Request Statement](https://www.bloomberg.com/notices/law-enforcement/); (b) protect the interests, rights, safety, or property of Bloomberg or others; (c) monitor compliance with and enforce any terms of service on this Web site; (d) provide our services and products (including allowing a purchaser of Bloomberg or a Bloomberg division to continue to serve you); (e) perform other activities related to such services and products, including billing and collection; (f) provide you with offers or promotions from Bloomberg; or (g) operate the systems that provide our services and products properly. 

The collection, further use, and/or disclosure of your information by Third-Party Providers or by other third parties is not the responsibility of Bloomberg. Rather, such collection, use, and/or disclosure is governed by the third parties’ privacy policies.

## Accuracy, Security, and Retention of Your Personal Information

Any personal information you provide to Bloomberg is kept on secure servers. Bloomberg uses security measures appropriate to the provision of the relevant product or service, such as reasonable administrative, technical, personnel, and physical measures (a) to safeguard personal information against loss, theft, unauthorized use, disclosure, or modification; and (b) to ensure the integrity of the personal information. To help us protect your privacy, you should maintain the secrecy of the logon ID and password you may have set up in connection with your participation in this Web site’s service. Personal information is retained for as long as is necessary for the purpose for which it is collected, including legitimate business reasons, and/or legal and regulatory requirements. 

## Rights with Respect to Your Personal Information

Depending on the jurisdiction, you may have the right to access, correct, delete, or restrict use of certain personal information covered by this Privacy Policy. Depending on the jurisdiction, you may also have the right to request that we refrain from processing personal information. Please bear in mind that if you exercise such rights this may affect our ability to provide our products and services. For inquiries about your personal information, please contact us by clicking [here](http://www.bloomberg.com/datainquiry). While Bloomberg will make reasonable efforts to accommodate your request, we also reserve the right to impose certain restrictions and requirements on such requests, if allowed or required by applicable laws.

Please note that it may take some time to process your request, consistent with applicable law.

## Transfer of Your Personal Information to Other Countries

Some of the uses and disclosures mentioned in this Privacy Policy may involve the transfer and processing of your personal information to and in various countries that may have different levels of privacy protection than your country. By using our products and services, you consent to such transfers and processing, including to and in the United States. Bloomberg’s Intra-Group Personal Data Protection Statement provides additional information about the transfer of personal information from the EU, EEA, and Switzerland to the United States and is available [here](https://www.bloomberg.com/notices/iga-statement/).

## Links to Third-Party Websites

Bloomberg may provide links to third-party websites, including social networking websites. Since we do not control third-party sites and are not responsible for any information you may provide while on such sites, we encourage you to read the privacy policies on those websites before providing any of your information on such sites.

## Questions Regarding This Privacy Policy

If you have questions regarding this Privacy Policy, please contact us at [privacy@bloomberg.com](mailto:privacy@bloomberg.com). Please include “Privacy” in the Subject line of your inquiry. If you have complaints about Bloomberg’s processing of your personal information, you may have the right to contact the applicable supervisory authority.

## Your California Privacy Rights

If you are a California resident, California Civil Code Section 1798.83 permits you to request information regarding the disclosure of your personal information by Bloomberg L.P. to its affiliates and/or third parties for their direct marketing purposes.

To make such a request, please send an email with your first name, last name, mailing address, email address and telephone number to [privacy@bloomberg.com](mailto:privacy@bloomberg.com). Please include “California Privacy Rights” in the Subject line of your email.

You may also make such a request by writing to us at:  
Bloomberg L.P.  
Attn: Legal Department  
731 Lexington Avenue  
New York, NY 10022

## Modifications to This Privacy Policy

Bloomberg reserves the right to change this Privacy Policy at any time by posting revisions on this Web page. Such changes will be effective upon posting.
